insideclimatenews.org 2018-12-26

# Privacy & Legal Policies | InsideClimate News

### Privacy

This privacy policy describes the circumstances under which we collect, use and share information about you through your use of InsideClimate News at [https://insideclimatenews.org](https://insideclimatenews.org/).

By accessing this site, you agree to be legally bound by and comply with this User Agreement. If you do not agree to comply with this User Agreement, you are not authorized to use this site. This site is not directed to children under 13, and will not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from children under 13. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.

You can visit our site without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. We collect data about you, such as your name, address and email address, only when you sign up for our newsletters, donate to us, become a member, apply for a job, or otherwise submit this information to us voluntarily. Non-personal information is collected through technology, which includes tracking information collected by us as well as third parties. We do not share your personal data with third parties other than some common service providers, which use your information to deliver newsletters, allow donation opportunities, monitor and analyze trends, and improve our website. Services accessible through our site may place cookies on your computer, and we are not responsible for their privacy policies.

These are services you can find on InsideClimate News:

  * Sharing buttons for [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/help/325807937506242), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy), [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) and other social media services, which appear on article pages.

  * [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en), which we use to measure site traffic.

  * [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/), which we use to manage newsletter subscriber, donor and other identifiable user data.

  * [WisePops](https://support.wisepops.com/more-info/data-and-cookie-policy), which we use for pop-up ads to collect email addresses for newsletter subscriptions and communicate updates.

  * [YouTube](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?hl=en) and [Vimeo](https://vimeo.com/privacy), which we use to host videos and embed them on our website.

  * [Facebook Instant Articles](http://www.facebookinstantarticle.com/privacy-policy/), which we use to collect email addresses for newsletter sign-ups directly through Facebook.

Remember that no data transmitted over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. You provide us with data at your own risk. Our servers are located in the United States. If you are located outside of the U.S., by sending us your data you consent to its transfer to and storage within the United States.

Below are the circumstances under which we will collect data from you.

_Newsletters_

If you sign-up for our newsletters, we and third parties will collect your email address and usage information relating to your receipt and viewership of any newsletters. We may use this information to send newsletters, updates and policy changes to your email address.

_Donations and Membership_

If you donate to InsideClimate News, we and our service providers will collect your first and last name, zip code, postal address, email address, donation amount, reason for donating, billing information and payment card information. InsideClimate News does not share, trade, sell, or otherwise release donors' personal information to any third parties. Individuals who give $35 a year or more will have their name published on our website and in our annual report. 

_Data Analytics_

We and our service providers may collect your usage information via an IP address and store it in our log files. We and our service providers may use this information to monitor and analyze website trends and usage, and improve our website.

_Videos_

If you watch videos through a third party video tool on our website, the third party video service will collect usage information. We cannot limit access by third parties to your information. If you choose to access our content outside of our website, you do so at your own risk.

### Your Choices

_Opting-Out_

If you prefer not to receive emails from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email. If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [newsletters@insideclimatenews.org](mailto:newsletters@insideclimatenews.org), and[ ](mailto:newsletters@insideclimatenews.org)provide your email address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe. We are not responsible for third-party opt-outs.

_Accessing and Changing Your Information_

Depending on your location, you may access, update, or request deletion of your personal information or usage data by sending an email to [newsletters@insideclimatenews.org](mailto:newsletters@insideclimatenews.org). If such information has been collected by third parties, you will need to contact those third parties directly about how to obtain and/or remove your information.

### Copyright and Links

Copyright in this site and the materials included in it, unless otherwise indicated, is owned by InsideClimate News. We do grant permission for republishing our original work upon request on a case by case basis. If you believe that your work has been copied, by us or by any third party on our site in a manner that constitutes copyright infringement, please contact us.

Please note that it is prohibited to download, republish, retransmit, or reproduce material we license from third parties.  

You may link to the home page of our site as long as the link does not cast us in a false or misleading light. You may not frame the content of our site.

Our site may contain links to other websites that we think may be of interest to you. We have no control over these other sites or their content. You should be aware when you leave our site for another that other sites are governed by their own user agreements and privacy policies, which you should be sure to read.

### Important Legal Information

Disclaimers and Limitation of Liability: Although we intend to take reasonable steps to prevent the introduction of viruses, worms, "Trojan Horses" or other destructive materials to our site, we do not guarantee or warrant that our site or materials that may be downloaded from our site are free from such destructive features. We are not liable for any damages or harm attributable to such features. We are not liable for any claim, loss or injury based on errors, omissions, interruptions or other inaccuracies in our site, nor for any claim, loss or injury that results from your use of this site or your breach of any provision of this user agreement.

Termination: We reserve the right to terminate the site and this User Agreement at any time without notice for any reason, including, in the case of the User Agreement, for your violation of any of its provisions. The Limitation of Liability and Governing Law Sections of this User Agreement shall survive any such termination.

Governing Law: This User Agreement will be governed by the laws of the State of New York applicable to contracts made and performed there without regard to its conflicts of law principles. You agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the state and federal courts sitting in the State and County of New York and waive any jurisdictional, venue or inconvenient forum objections to such courts.

_Last updated May 25, 2018._
